leftlanenews.com 2019-07-11

# - LeftLaneNews

##  Version 1.4

Below is a description of the collection of visitor information that takes place when you visit this website.

 **User Information**

When you visit LeftLaneNews.com, your Web browser transmits certain information to our servers in the form of an HTTP request. Specifically, unless otherwise configured, your browser will broadcast its type (i.e. Chrome, Firefox, Edge, etc), its version, and the version of your device's operating system (i.e. Windows 10, iOS 11, etc). This information (referred to as "user agent" data) is temporarily stored and processed by our servers to insure optimal compatibility between the content served (images, video, html, etc) and your device. The user agent data often also includes the referring website, if applicable (i.e. the web page on which you clicked a link to this website). This information is not personally identifiable, and is not stored by LeftLaneNews.com in a database or any other type of persistent storage. Similarly, we use javascript to make real time requests to your browser for information about your screen resolution, color bit depth, window scroll position, cursor position, and time on page, in order to customize the website's interface and content according to those parameters. As with user agent data, this information is not logged, nor is it correlated to, or combined with, any other data sets.

Additionally, your IP address is exposed to our servers any time you initiate a connection to this website. LeftLaneNews.com stores IP addresses and the date/time of each connection in standard server log files for a period of time not exceeding 60 days. Your IP address can be used to determine the physical location of your Internet Service Provider, which is often the city from which you are accessing the Web. Under normal circumstances, we do not use visitor IP address information for any purpose other than to, if possible, connect you to the nearest server hosting our content. Server logs are retained for the aforementioned time period as a security precaution and for troubleshooting purposes.

In cases of inappropriate or illegal conduct, IP addresses and other technical markers, combined with any other information available, may be used to ban users, or in some cases may be relayed to law enforcement, if a crime against LeftLaneNews or its users is suspected to have taken place during or in relation to visits to this website. At no time will LeftLaneNews.com share server logs or user IP addresses with any third parties other than law enforcement agencies and the internet service provider that owns the address. No effort is made to correlate or combine server logs with any other information.

Although LeftLaneNews does not directly store or process User Agent data or IP addresses for any reason other than those described above, there are multiple third-party services incorporated into this website that do. The following third-party components collect and process User Agent, IP address, and "cookie" data in an anonymized or pseudonymized fashion:

  * Google Analytics
  * DoubleClick by Google
  * Disqus
  * Jumpstart Automotive Media
  * Advertisers whose ads are displayed via DFP

Google Analytics provides LeftLaneNews.com with detailed statistical data based on User Agent, IP, and cookie data. Google Analytics does not expose IP addresses or any personally identifiable user data to LeftLaneNews.com. Google stores data in accordance with its privacy policy, which includes strict user protections. LeftLaneNews.com does not under any circumstances cross reference data from Google Analytics with server logs or other metrics to de-anonymize users or perform any other kind of analysis outside of the Analytics software.

When you sign up to post comments on this website, you must do so in accordance with the privacy policy set out by Disqus. 

**Third-party** **advertising**

The advertisements displayed on LeftLaneNews.com are served by a third-party advertising network. Advertisements served through the DoubleClick network, in connection with our partnership with Jumpstart Automotive Media, are sometimes targeted based on geolocation (derived from IP addresses), and can also be targeted using anonymized user interest profiles controlled by Google/Doubleclick or Jumpstart Automotive Media.

These companies may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to target advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. Such "interest-based advertising" is targeted via 'cookies'.

In the case of vehicle price quotes, the data you volunteer in the form is securely passed along to car dealerships in your area, and might be stored by Leftlane or Jumpstart Automotive Group for statistical analysis only. Under no circumstances will personally identifiable information collected via car price quote forms be used for any other marketing purpose, or distributed to any additional third parties outside of Jumpstart and the relevant car dealerships. 

**Cookies**

Cookies contain alphanumeric strings that can be decoded when the website loads, to automatically return to the browser or a script information gathered at a previous time. Cookies are used for purposes like remembering your username in the comments area, while other cookies can be used to target ads based on your advertising interest profile. Cookie data is not stored on the server, and therefore, not available for viewing by LeftLaneNews.com or the aforementioned third parties. Industry best practices are employed to mitigate the risk of any exploitation of this data by malicious software on your computer, on the website, or in the code of other websites. Always keep your operating system and browser up to date to maximize personal security.

  * The Google advertising privacy policy (applicable to DoubleClick) can be found here: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads
  * The Disqus privacy policy can be found here: https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy
  * If you are in the U.S. or Canada and would like to opt-out of interest-based advertising cookies, please visit: http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/
  * If you are in Europe or the UK and would like to opt-out of interest-based advertising cookies, please visit: http://www.youronlinechoices.com/
  * To permanently opt out of Google's DoubleClick cookie: https://support.google.com/ads/answer/7395996
  * To opt-out of Google Analytics cookies, please visit: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en

We are committed to continuing to protect the privacy of our readers. If you have any additional questions, please contact us.

We recommend that you review this Privacy Statement periodically, as it is subject to change.
